Improved & Synced by BanglarBagh
(♪♪♪)
(FAINT RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING INTENSIFIES)
(WHOOSHING)
(OBJECTS CLANKING)
(LOUD THUD)
(OBJECTS CONTINUE CLANKING)
(♪♪♪)
(INDISTINCT VOICES OVER COMM)
(RHYTHMIC BEEPING)
MIRANDA: This is Dr. Miranda North
quarantine officer on board
the International Space Station.
Today the Pilgrim capsule
with its valuable Mars soil samples
completes its eight-month return from Mars.
Preparing to receive these samples
has been the purpose of our mission
these last few months.
But the Pilgrim capsule is damaged.
At 0630 UTC  Pilgrim was struck by debris
and veered off course.
Rory Adams will spacewalk
to establish visual contact
with the incoming space capsule
and he will grab it with a remote arm.
We've been waiting a long time
for this sample
and Rory is placing himself at great risk
to secure it.
Over and out.
DAVID: EMU at 4.7 psi  pure O2.
RORY: Is that how you're gonna do it?
I wouldn't do it that way.
KAT: Dr. Jordan  status?
RORY: Come on  faster  faster  faster.
DAVID: Nitrogen at near zero.
KAT: Dr. North?
MIRANDA: I'm in the airlock.
RORY: Faster  faster  faster. Come on.
KAT: Rory  slow to go fast.
RORY: Or fast to go fast.
KAT: Deliberate.
RORY: What does she have against fast?
KAT: Remember
eight billion people.
MIRANDA: Rory  if you can't save it...
RORY: Yeah  spoiler alert.
I'm fucking saving it.
MIRANDA: But if you can't  Rory
just push the capsule into deep space  okay?
- Do you hear me?
- RORY: Can you get OCD...
Sorry  CDC out of my face?
'Cause I got a big operation.
I need to concentrate.
- MIRANDA: I just want you...
- I can't... I can't hear you...
- I love you  too.
- ...at all.
DAVID: EMU at 4.7 psi  pure O2.
Where's the remote?
- Here. The arm's yours.
- There you go.
- Full manual.
- All right  he knows. Let's go.
SHO: Careful with... Sorry  you know this.
Yeah  yeah. No more sorries.
- KAT: Miranda  to the Cupola  please.
- All right  that's it.
Yep.
(♪♪♪)
(WHIRRING)
(SLOW  STEADY BEEPING)
(♪♪♪)
KAT: (OVER COMM) David?
Are you on your way?
On my way.
- Slow  Sho.
- SHO: Excuse me.
How do you say "breathe" in Japanese?
Kokyu shiro.
This was supposed to be routine.
RORY: (OVER COMM) The airlock is sealed.
I am walking.
KAT: 4:35 UTC.
After striking debris
Pilgrim non-responsive.
Inbound on collision course with ISS.
Initiating emergency course correction
and manual retrieval.
SHO: Canadarm online.
Transferring control to wireless.
KAT: Station to Control.
- Initiating sequence.
- GROUND CONTROL: Affirmative.
SHO: So  the committee?
KAT: You let me worry
about the committee.
Where's Rory?
He is at risk out there.
RORY: Easy  folks. Mics are live.
You ready  Sho?
SHO: Thrusters up.
(RUMBLING)
(BEEPING)
RORY: Moving into position.
I have control of the arm.
(♪♪♪)
HUGH: Your worry lines are showing.
Yeah  well  I get paid by the line.
- HUGH: I have a good feeling about this.
- Yeah?
HUGH: Rory's gonna deliver that sample.
MIRANDA: Right to your lab.
(LIGHT RUMBLING)
(CREAKING)
KAT: Prepare for course correction.
.050-niner by.076.
- Remember your training.
- We never trained for this.
KAT: On my mark.
Five  four  three  two  one.
(CLICK  BEEP)
(DEEP RUMBLING  SHUDDERING)
(BEEPING  WHIRRING)
(RUMBLING  SHUDDERING
GRADUALLY STOP)
KAT: New capsule trajectory
negative 0.50.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Proximity alert.
Proximity alert.
KAT: Ignore the proximity alert.
New station trajectory  negative.32.
The capsule will miss us. Just.
- Rory?
- I'm still downrange.
And it's coming in shallow.
Any moment now. Eight  maybe nine o'clock.
I'm having fun.
- Are you guys having fun?
- DAVID: Rory  if you miss...
Yeah  yeah  yeah.
If...
Just gonna skip off the atmosphere
like a flat stone on water.
Just fly off into nowhere.
It's no harm done.
RORY: (EXHALES) Okay.
There.
- There.
- RORY: I see it.
All right  here we go
here we go  here we go.
This is fun.
SHO: Rory  you have to move.
It's gonna hit you.
- No  it's not.
- Please  Rory  move.
KAT: Station to Control.
Visual confirmation of
Mars Capsule Pilgrim.
RORY: I used to play catcher
but only in tee-ball.
- MIRANDA: Rory?
- Not now.
Not now.
No  come on  come here  come here
come on  come on  come on.
(LOUD BOOM  DEEP RUMBLING)
(CREAKING  RATTLING)
Rory?
- Rory?
- MIRANDA: Rory?
(RORY LAUGHING)
HUGH: (LAUGHS) He got it.
MIRANDA: Yes!
(RORY COUGHING  LAUGHING)
RORY: Oh  Hugh?
Cue Instagram!
HUGH: I didn't want to jinx it.
(RORY GRUNTS)
Point and shoot  motherfucker!
HUGH: (CHUCKLES) Okay  okay.
(CAMERA CLICKS  WHIRRS)
(RORY WHOOPS)
(RORY LAUGHS)
(RORY COUGHS)
RORY: Mars Capsule in locked position.
(SHO CHUCKLES)
(RORY WHOOPS)
(RORY LAUGHS)
Whoo...
I'm coming home.
This is Mission Commander
Ekaterina Golovkina.
Tell the committee
Pilgrim's landed on Plymouth Rock.
The Mars samples are safe and sound.
Copy that  Commander.
Congratulations.
(♪♪♪)
(SQUEAKS SOFTLY)
(CLICKING)
HUGH: Ready?
(ELECTRONIC DING)
KAT: We are recording.
0640 UTC.
HUGH: Pilgrim wasn't just seeing things
in Mars' soil.
We're looking at a large single cell.
Inert.
Unmistakably biological.
And  like organisms on Earth
has what appears to be
a nucleus  cytoplasm...
(OVER COMM) The cell wall is thick.
Those hairs look like cilia.
Longer than we're used to seeing on Earth.
More like flagella.
- What's our temperature?
- SHO: Minus 110.
Start bringing it up.
SHO: Minus 82.
HUGH: Even quicker.
SHO: Minus 55.
This is some Re-Animator shit.
Oh  that's a very obscure reference.
- Not for a nerd.
- Not if you're a nerd.
(HUGH CHUCKLES)
SHO: Minus 17.
Zero degrees.
HUGH: (EXHALES) Oh  come on.
SHO: Eighteen...
Nineteen...
20 degrees Celsius.
Nothing.
Update?
I'm gonna try a different atmosphere.
Closer to Proterozoic Earth
than today's Mars.
Less oxygen...
More carbon dioxide.
(CLICK  BEEP)
And then  when Sho's ready
a growth medium.
In this case  glucose.
(PANTING)
(WHISPERS) Come on  dance.
(♪♪♪)
MIRANDA: Did it just move?
Hugh?
HUGH: Oh.
(CHUCKLING SOFTLY)
HUGH: My God.
(GASPS)
MIRANDA: It worked. You woke it.
We're looking at
the first incontrovertible proof
of life beyond Earth.
(LAUGHS QUIETLY)
(CHUCKLING)
Oh  it's beautiful.
(♪♪♪)
VARGAS: Our first question is from Allen.
He's nine years old.
And  Allen  what is your question
for Commander Golovkina?
Is it green?
It isn't visible at all  actually.
It's microscopic.
A single cell.
To put it into perspective
your body is made up of trillions.
There's an alien inside of me?
Oh  I bet your teacher sometimes thinks so.
MUIR: Well  we have another question
from 8-year-old Mari.
Are you bringing the alien back to Earth?
No  we're gonna keep it up here.
We're gonna study it where it's safe.
MUIR: Commander?
The ISS is the most expensive house
ever built.
$200 billion American
and counting.
Because we keep adding rooms.
It flies around Earth 16 times a day.
In 30 years
over 100 people have lived here
thanks to generous countries
like Russia  the USA  and China.
We call this Tranquility Node.
Dr. Jordan here is about to break the
record for consecutive days in space.
Four hundred and seventy-three  straight.
Your mommy must miss you.
(LAUGHS)
Ah  she does.
But I have family here.
Yeah  the kind that teases him
'cause his mommy misses him.
KAT: This is one of
our newest crew members.
Miranda North from
the Centers for Disease Control.
She's a doctor  too.
You guys are witnessing a space triathlon.
Yeah  I'm winning.
VARGAS: We have another question
from 7-year-old Leila.
We think this question
is a little personal.
- Go ahead.
- How do you go to the bathroom?
Funnel
tube
and some suction.
Everything we do on the ISS
is like everything you do on Earth.
Except different. Do you like peas?
ALLEN: Yep.
Mmm! Mmm! Mmm!
So  have you got a name yet?
MUIR: For that  we want to go down live
just outside our studio in Times Square
to one very brave classmate.
- VARGAS: Hi  Dominique.
- Hi.
Calvin Coolidge Elementary
was chosen among 11 000 schools
for this honor.
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
We name the Martian
after our school.
"Calvin."
(CHEERING)
RORY: Control? Control?
If you're listening  and you probably are
'cause you're creepy that way
can I just rant for a second
about the micromanagement?
We're not blood-filled meat puppets.
I come from a long line of plumbers.
I can fix a shower.
If I can't...
Well  Hugh doesn't shower anyway
he's British.
- First international incident.
- I'm not being critical of you.
You're just a very under-bathed nation.
Everybody knows it.
Don't be an ugly American.
Wow. Who's ugly now?
I nailed Step 17.
I'm a very good-looking American
you know? Oh  I see  it's right there.
Control  I'm sorry about him.
KAT: Rory  Control can't hear you.
I don't know where rage
like that comes from.
- Can you please fix the shower?
- Twenty-eight steps to fix a shower.
Ah. You know  I can do this myself.
No  I know. You just haven't.
Doctors are always so bad
at looking after themselves  aren't they?
(RAPID ELECTRONIC CLICKING)
(CLICKING STOPS)
You've spent too much time up here  David.
Your atrophy's accelerated.
And you're close to your radiation limit.
You noticed any  um  glowing in the dark?
(CHUCKLES)
DAVID: Hmm.
I like it up here.
When I was in the military
we'd go to Syria.
You know.
We'd set up a hospital
treat all the casualties
and then we'd come back a week...
A week or two later
and then the whole village
would just be bombed out.
MIRANDA: Mmm.
Then Earth isn't all Syria  though  is it?
(RAPID BEEPING)
I can't stand what we do
to each other down there.
MIRANDA: But it's home  and it's beautiful.
Don't you miss anything?
Don't you miss fresh water or birds
or the trees?
(♪♪♪)
(LOW ELECTRONIC HUMMING)
I like the hum up here.
(DAVID INHALES DEEPLY)
And the air.
Hmm.
(LAUGHS SOFTLY)
KAT: What you have achieved
with Calvin is remarkable  Hugh.
I haven't had a chance to say that.
HUGH: Thank you.
I think these will prove to be
the greatest days of my life.
I wish I had a time machine
so I could visit the 10-year-old me.
KAT: Did he want to be an astronaut?
HUGH: He wanted out of the wheelchair.
KAT: And how does he feel now?
Like a bird.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Oh  don't get me wrong.
I don't hate my chair.
I love it.
For the sake of the anonymous genius
who invented it.
You're one of a kind  Hugh.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Good night.
(♪♪♪)
(BEEP)
SHO: 11:20 UTC.
HUGH: Hold on to your helmets.
The glucose intake is very rapid.
(OVER COMM) The specimen's cells
have begun to move together
en masse as a unit.
They're also sharing electrical activity
in what resembles a growing neural network.
Notice I didn't say "brain."
Dr. North speaking.
It is our educated opinion
that this new species is not a colony
of fast-dividing single-celled organisms
but one larger  solitary organism
composed of trillions
of identical cooperative cells.
Here's what's fascinating.
I mean  it's all fascinating  isn't it?
Unlike most multicellular organisms
every cell of Calvin's can perform
every somatic function on its own.
Every single cell is
simultaneously a muscle cell
and a nerve cell and a photoreceptive cell.
So the creature  as a whole
is  in a very real sense  all muscle
all brain  all eye.
HUGH: As such  Calvin now possesses
the means to interact with its environment
including the use of
what appears to be proto-appendages.
I'll demonstrate.
(♪♪♪)
(GASPS SOFTLY)
But notice how it's approaching
and not retreating.
HUGH: Its curiosity outweighs its fear.
(♪♪♪)
That's beautiful.
(CHUCKLES)
(♪♪♪)
Hello  Calvin.
RORY: How's that feel  Hugh?
You're gonna be a daddy.
There's gonna be
a big custody battle over this one.
- (LAUGHTER)
- (SINGING) And if you feel
- Like I feel  baby
- DAVID: One day  we're all gonna die
and I want to know if there'd be
even the possibility of having...
- Let's get it on
- (LAUGHING)
Hey  let's get it on...
DAVID: I'm getting a little nauseous.
(WOMAN SQUEALING IN PAIN)
You can do this  Kazumi.
I'm doing my best.
It's coming.
Any moment now  okay  push.
Easy for you to say.
You can do it  Kazumi.
(SQUEALING INTENSIFIES)
You can do it  you can do it.
Sho...
I can see it. Okay  push.
It's okay.
Push.
You'll be able to meet Mei soon.
You can do it.
"...and that there was more of it
during the night."
"We can observe  too
how the recollection of a dream "
"which was still lively in the morning "
"will melt away
except for a few small fragments..."
RORY: This book doesn't have pictures in it
does it?
HUGH: Obviously not.
Would you prefer
that I don't read it out loud?
- That's beautiful.
- HUGH: Beautiful.
(ALL LAUGHING)
- Oh  he makes me cry.
- SHO: Hi  guys. Guys.
- Meet Mei.
- ALL: Hey! Oh!
(CHEERING  LAUGHING)
- Hi  Mei!
- HUGH: Hey  Mei!
- Say hi to everybody  Mei.
- Hi  Mei.
HUGH: She's beautiful!
RORY: Congratulations.
Thank you. Nice to meet you.
Do they have any idea who the father is?
- Shut up.
- HUGH: Another one  another one.
SHO: (CHUCKLES) Okay.
For story time.
It was my favorite.
You might say my first foray into space.
SHO: Oh  thank you so much.
KAZUMI: Thank you  Commander.
- Thank you  guys.
RORY: She's beautiful  Sho.
Thank you!
- HUGH: Yay!
- No  seriously  that kid had blue eyes.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
(♪♪♪)
(SPEAKS OTHER LANGUAGE)
(GASPS SOFTLY)
(CHUCKLES)
(SOFT  TREMBLING BREATHS)
(♪♪♪)
(RUMBLING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Fuck.
(RAPID BEEPING)
RORY: It's the lab.
(ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
(BEEPING)
(CLICK  BUZZ)
(WHOOSHING)
(CLOSES DOOR)
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(ALARM STOPS)
Okay. Miranda
check the O2 in the lab. Is it...
O2's on 21. We're clear for contamination.
We're okay. Calvin's safe.
I don't understand how this happened.
Nothing in that lab can malfunction.
A clamp. It failed.
- It's on me.
- RORY: Yeah  no shit it's on you.
A dizzy 5-year-old could have spotted that.
MIRANDA: Protecting these firewalls
yes  that's my job.
But I can't do it alone.
Kibo wasn't designed
for strict firewall lockdown
and neither was the station.
There is zero precedent for any of this.
But you do not come out of that lab
without triple-checking everything.
You do not go into that lab
without a proper rest.
For all I know
we're carrying anthrax onboard.
You can't compare Calvin to anthrax.
Yeah  I know at least five guys
back home who can do my job.
(PANTING)
Nobody can do yours except you.
I don't want to be around that thing.
I'm not qualified to be around that thing.
- HUGH: I understand.
- Good.
I'm just saying
you can't compare Calvin to anthrax.
RORY: Stop...
Stop calling it fucking "Calvin."
We don't know what that thing is. Yeah?
And you're in there
and you're playing around with it
like it's your buddy.
I'm your buddy.
You're drunk on this. Wake up.
MIRANDA: This isn't and will never be
a controlled experiment.
So let's all agree
we made our first and last mistake.
I miss my fucking dog.
Good night.
(♪♪♪)
MIRANDA: Dr. Miranda North
quarantine officer  2320 UTC.
After weeks of stunning
growth and activity
Calvin is completely inactive.
We believe it's likely due to
the clamp failure in the lab
which caused a temporary change
of air pressure in Calvin's box.
Our working theory is that
this hibernation
may be a defense mechanism.
Everyone here is on edge
and Hugh  of course
has been beating himself up
but  honestly  I'm relieved.
Calvin was growing very fast
and this has now given me time
to reinforce firewall precautions
with the crew.
The box must stay sealed
the lab must stay sealed
no matter the risk to Calvin.
HUGH: It's just floating.
Because of my mistake in the lab.
And it was going so well.
(MIRANDA CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
What?
Something my dad used to say.
"It was all going so well."
HUGH: I'm toying with the idea
of stimulating it electrically.
- What do you think?
- That's not my call.
But if it were?
(EXHALES)
I don't know.
My job is lines of defense.
Imagine the worst thing
that could ever happen
and then the worst after that
and the worst after that  and then I...
- I've planned for all of them.
- HUGH: I understand that.
But risks are taken for reasons.
Because of Calvin
we're gonna learn so much about life.
Its origin  its nature
maybe even its meaning.
- No  I know.
- You're a doctor.
Um  stem cell research.
What if Calvin could make
stem cells obsolete?
Help cure the incurable...
Reverse the irreversible.
I have to fix this.
Good. Are you ready?
- Stretch.
- HUGH: Okay.
And relax.
(BEEPING)
Ready.
You sure it won't hurt it?
(ELECTRICAL CRACKLE)
It's a very  very low voltage.
We're only stimulating it.
RORY: What exactly are you hoping for?
HUGH: I'm hoping to wake him up.
We're seeing under what conditions
it reengages with its environment.
(SQUEAKS)
RORY: Come on in.
We're shocking the monkey.
(CRACKLES)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Trying another spot.
(HUGH SIGHS)
(CRACKLES)
HUGH: Nothing.
Not even at a cellular level.
Are you sure it's not  uh  dead?
HUGH: It's alive.
It's just in a deep sleep.
Oh  come on  Calvin.
Wake up.
(CRACKLES)
Shit!
(GROANS)
RORY: What's wrong?
HUGH: It broke the wand.
(RAPID BEEPING)
I'm gonna try and pull my hand out.
Do that  but just make sure
to protect the glove.
HUGH: (WHISPERS) Shit.
SHO: It's gripping the glass.
HUGH: Okay  okay.
(HAND SQUEAKS OVER GLASS)
(GRUNTING) Little sod.
MIRANDA: How hard is it holding on to you?
- Like a firm handshake.
- It's fine.
It doesn't hurt  but it's growing strong.
- KAT: What's the problem?
- It's got Hugh's hand.
His heart rate is at 165.
- Sho  can we trust the glove?
- It's very tight.
RORY: Glove's not going anywhere.
It's fine.
Shit.
Okay  but just relax. Tell him to relax.
- Derry? Derry  look at me.
- Tell him to calm down.
Look at me. Relax. Just relax your hand.
(GROANS  PANTS)
MIRANDA: Okay.
It's in between my fingers.
RORY: Can I make a suggestion?
Can I just...
Can I go in there and get him and...
No  you're not going to go in there.
No  of course you're not
because we have to maintain quarantine.
- Stop.
- No  I can do this. I can. I can do this. Um...
- Can you try and distract it?
- HUGH: Yes  yes.
Um  um  I'll see
if I can interest it in the wand.
(SQUEAKING)
Come on  my favorite little Martian.
Come on.
(PANTING  TREMBLING)
Oh!
He lost interest.
(GRUNTS)
It's got hold of my hand.
(LOW GRUNTING)
Ahh!
MIRANDA: Hugh?
RORY: Hugh?
Hugh?
(HUGH GASPING)
RORY: Hey  Hugh?
MIRANDA: Hugh?
(GRUNTING)
(SQUEAKING)
(FRANTIC GRUNTING)
(GASPING) Help me! Help me!
DAVID: What the fuck is going on?
MIRANDA: No  no one's going in!
- Come on. Who's going in?
- Wait!
- Wait for fucking what?
- RORY: Screw it. I'm going in there.
Don't do this.
(GASPING BREATHS)
(YELLS)
I don't give a shit
about your fucking quarantine!
There's nothing to protect you.
You're not going in there.
Who gives you the fucking jurisdiction?
- Just open the door  Rory.
- Wait  wait.
(GASPING BREATHS)
MIRANDA: You're not going in there.
DAVID: Let him in!
MIRANDA: You're not going in there. No.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
- Wait  wait  wait.
- MIRANDA: You're not going in.
RORY: He's out.
He's out.
Guys  look at it.
RORY: Aw  Jesus.
DAVID: What are his vitals?
126 and dropping.
What's it doing?
Holy shit.
Jesus Christ.
RORY: You guys got eyes on it anywhere?
Okay  there. There.
(SQUEAKING)
RORY: Guys?
(SQUEALING)
(WHIMPERS)
(CRACKLING)
RORY: Fuck this.
MIRANDA: No!
KAT: Let him go.
RORY: Hey  buddy.
(ALARM BLARING)
KAT: Watch his hand.
MIRANDA: There we go.
SHO: It's there.
Get him in. Adams!
(GASPING)
- Yeah.
- MIRANDA: David  I need you here.
KAT: Rory  I can't let you out.
Aw  shit.
DAVID: Oh  gosh.
MIRANDA: There we go.
SHO: Hugh? Hugh?
- Look at me.
- DAVID: Just listen to me for a second  okay?
RORY: Hey  guys?
MIRANDA: Sho  can you find a bandage?
Suggestions?
Get an oxygen candle.
- Burn it off.
- Yeah  yeah  yeah.
(HUGH GRUNTING)
MIRANDA: Just look at me.
Look at me. It's fine.
(PANTING)
(WHIRS)
(GRUNTS)
RORY: Fuck. (GRUNTS)
(EXHALES) Okay  all right  what now?
How do we get him out?
We need to get Calvin
back behind Firewall One
and once he's there  we can pull Rory out.
RORY: Fuck this.
Permission to fucking kill the thing.
Commander?
Kill it.
Sho?
- Any suggestions?
- What about the incinerator?
(STAMMERS) I like that.
All right  genius. Here.
SHO: Close the red valve.
Disengage the clamp.
Disconnect the hose.
Be careful  Rory.
- Fuck!
- SHO: There's limited fuel.
Copy. Okay.
- Manual override.
- Thank you.
Okay.
Rory  I...
Yeah.
(FLAME WHOOSHING)
(STRAINED GRUNT)
Fuck!
SHO: You're wasting too much fuel.
(STRAINED GRUNTING)
(YELLS) No!
(PANTING)
Fuck.
DAVID: Rory!
Rory!
Hey!
(PANTING)
KAT: Rory  stop. Stop.
MIRANDA: Rory!
(GRUNTS)
(GASPING BREATHS)
(BEEPING)
SHO: Rory? You're out of fuel.
(FAINT CLINKING)
(PANTING)
(FAINT THUMPING)
It's behind you!
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING WEAKLY)
(CHOKING)
(WHISPERS) Jesus.
(WHISPERS) Fuck.
DAVID: Somebody open the fucking door!
Open the portal now! Just open the portal.
There's a man in there getting strangled.
- Rory? What is he saying? Rory?
- I can't  no matter what's happening.
DAVID: Kat. Kat! We got to open the door!
- No! No one's going in! It's protocol!
- Rory?
DAVID: What is this fucking protocol?
MIRANDA: Jordan  no!
- Just open the portal!
- Rory?
DAVID: There's a man dying in there!
MIRANDA: Nobody open the fucking...
MIRANDA: Rory  look at me  look at me.
DAVID: Rory  we can't hear you
if you take your comm out.
MIRANDA: I need to see what's happening!
DAVID: Rory! Rory?
MIRANDA: Rory!
MIRANDA: Will you turn around?
Can you turn around?
DAVID: There's a man dying in there!
We can't hear you if
you take your comm out!
MIRANDA: No! No  you are not going in!
HUGH: Help him!
DAVID: Open the door!
MIRANDA: Don't open the door  okay?
Don't open the door!
Stay back!
I need to see your face.
Can you turn around?
(CHOKING  GASPING)
(♪♪♪)
(SLOW  STEADY BEEPING)
(FLATLINING TONE)
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
(SQUISHING)
(♪♪♪)
(SHUDDERING BREATHS)
(WHISPERS) Guys.
Guys.
(ALARM BLARING)
Sho.
(ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
MIRANDA: That's so much bigger.
Jesus.
MIRANDA: Guys?
- Sho.
- MIRANDA: Guys  it's trying to get out.
The CPU overrode us.
MIRANDA: It's searching for a way out.
- The system won't give me access to it.
- KAT: Full manual.
MIRANDA: Shut them down  okay?
How smart is this thing?
It feels the airflow.
I can't control them all at once.
KAT: Then shut them one by one.
Seal the lab.
- Just shut it down! Shut it down now!
- KAT: We are on it.
(BEEPING)
(FAINT  MUFFLED THUMPING)
(MUFFLED THUMPING CONTINUES)
Guys  it's gone.
- It got out.
- KAT: Where did it go?
DAVID: Could be anywhere now.
MIRANDA: Firewall Two has failed.
(BREATH SHUDDERING)
(♪♪♪)
DAVID: Kat.
We need to reestablish quarantine.
KAT: And get a distress call out.
Control  this is Station.
Station for Control.
The specimen's location is unknown.
It is to be considered hostile and deadly.
Our intent is to isolate and destroy it
in compliance with protocol.
We'll continue said course of action
unless otherwise instructed.
- Please acknowledge and advise...
- Kat? Kat. We lost them.
- How much of that went out?
- Some.
I think.
There is no way to be sure.
Looks like communications just failed.
Can we talk to each other?
David. It's Kat.
Do you copy?
DAVID: Go for David.
So  we've lost contact with Earth.
(SIGHS) I don't think... Wait.
Yes  outside communications are down.
- Could the sprinklers affect comms?
- SHO: No.
They're independent systems.
Can we run a diagnostic from here?
(CLICKING  BEEPING)
SHO: The transmitter has failed.
But we have to go outside to access it
and get Earth back online.
Then I have to walk.
Let me.
No.
After Rory  I'm best qualified
for walk-and-repair.
DAVID: This is not protocol.
It's way too risky for
you to go out there and
fix the comms.
We don't know where Calvin is.
You haven't had your nitrogen detox.
Your health is my responsibility.
- I'll be fine.
- Yeah.
What is it you say?
"Slow is fast " right?
Yeah. Slow to go fast.
Yeah. Well  that's out the window.
We can escape in the lifeboats.
Earth is the responsibility.
Nothing goes down to the planet.
It was stipulated. In writing.
DAVID: What are you talking about?
What was stipulated in writing?
What was stipulated?
KAT: David  first things first.
When we're back in touch with Control
we'll turn our attention to Calvin.
Don't worry.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER OVER COMM)
MIRANDA: Rate  61 beats a minute.
Pressure  97 over 53.
I'd hate to see you relaxed.
DAVID: But she is relaxed. Aren't you  Kat?
SHO: Suit's running warm.
KAT: Like Siberia in summer.
(LOW GASP)
I'm at the transmitter.
Commencing on-site diagnostic.
It's overheated.
I can tell.
SHO: How?
I see scorching.
I want to check the coolant levels.
Is it possible
Calvin could have gotten into coolant?
Possible.
We have to know.
- There is the issue.
- HUGH: Commander?
It's bone-dry.
HUGH: Calvin is a carbon-based organism.
It needs food  water
and oxygen  just like us.
We have to consider the possibility
it consumed the coolant for food.
David  could you list
all the water sources aboard?
Pure or otherwise.
DAVID: Uh  there's plenty
of drinking water
there's coolant for the comms
coolant for the CPU...
Um... There's coolant for the spacesuits.
(GASPS)
MIRANDA: Commander?
KAT: Calvin just came out.
It grabbed my suit.
It's bigger.
It's trying to get in.
SHO: Trust your suit.
MIRANDA: Can it breathe out there?
HUGH: No.
But it might be able to
store oxygen for a period of time.
I'm closing the valve.
(PANTING  TREMBLING)
It's squeezing.
HUGH: Kat. Kat  are you okay?
Yes. The suit's thick enough.
It's twisting up your leg.
Go. Go to the airlock now.
Aw  fuck this. I'm headed for the airlock.
I'm burning this fucker off.
SHO: Kat  focus on meeting David.
We'll worry about the comms later.
Sho?
There's liquid in the helmet.
Calvin must have broken my coolant loop.
Kat  there is enough coolant.
KAT: Yes  I know.
I know.
(FOOTSTEPS THUMPING)
David  meet me at the airlock.
What? Yeah. Go  go  go!
KAT: It's squeezing harder.
DAVID: Calvin cracked
the coolant system in her suit.
HUGH: Commander  Calvin knows
exactly what it's doing.
It's growing smarter.
The liquid  it's blocking my vision.
I don't have time.
I've got to jump.
- SHO: Kat  the tether won't reach.
- I'm unclipping.
- SHO: Kat?
- No comments!
I've got to jump.
(GRUNTS)
(RUMBLING)
(GASPS)
(MUFFLED GRUNTING)
MIRANDA: David
I've taken Kat off the channel.
Look  she's not gonna tell you this
but her heart is beating out of her chest.
She's drowning.
So just be prepared
she may not be rational.
DAVID: Copy that.
Sho  I have no time for EVA.
I'm using the launch suit.
- SHO: It's not designed for this.
- I know.
- There's not enough protection.
- I know. Don't worry.
MIRANDA: Kat is less than a minute out.
DAVID: Vent the airlock.
- SHO: What about decompression?
- Just do it.
- It's gonna hurt.
- Come on  do it!
- Is your helmet sealed?
- Sho!
(WHOOSHING)
(SCREAMING)
(PAINED GRUNTING)
(LOW  GASPING BREATHS)
SHO: Guys  we are running out of time.
(GRUNTS)
(MUFFLED GRUNTING)
DAVID: Kat  Kat! Don't swallow it.
It's toxic  okay?
I need you to help me open the valve.
We're gonna do this together.
Okay?
(LOUD GASPING)
I'm gonna pull down
and you're gonna go clockwise
from your side.
(GASPING BREATHS)
Okay?
DAVID: There you go.
Good  good  good.
(LABORED BREATHING)
Don't worry about Calvin.
We're gonna get you inside
and we're gonna get it off.
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING) David.
DAVID: Kat?
No  no  no. Clockwise from your side.
(WHEEZING GROAN)
Clockwise from your side.
Kat  come on.
- Miranda?
- MIRANDA: Yeah  I'm here.
She's fighting me!
She's turned her lever the wrong way.
Pull down...
(CREAKING)
(STRAINED GRUNTING)
Kat. You're fighting me  Kat. Come on.
We got to do it together  now.
- Come on. Kat  come on  please.
- MIRANDA: David.
DAVID: Kat!
- Kat. Kat!
- DAVID: Look at me!
Just pull on the lever! Okay?
(BEEPING)
Kat  come on! Come on!
Just pull down on the lever!
(MUFFLED GASPING)
MIRANDA: David...
DAVID: Kat!
Come on  you can do this!
MIRANDA: David  she's
doing it deliberately.
(FRANTIC GASPING)
Come on!
(GASPING QUIETS)
Kat!
- Kat!
- David  stop.
Stop.
She's not letting Calvin back in here.
Kat?
(QUIET CHOKING)
Commander.
(♪♪♪)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
(WHISPERS) Kat  Kat...
(♪♪♪)
(SOBBING QUIETLY)
What is going on?
(TREMBLING) What is going on?
(SOBBING)
(♪♪♪)
(MIRANDA SOBBING)
HUGH: Guys  guys  do you copy?
MIRANDA: Yeah.
- Yeah  I copy.
- Okay  okay  um...
Let's keep it together.
We may have...
We may have an opportunity here.
Calvin's ability to survive
in that vacuum and temperature
is astonishing.
But he can't live much longer out there.
Sho. Sho.
Are you sure that we've lost
all communication with Earth?
I am sure.
All right  then we have
to keep it out there.
MIRANDA: We have a new firewall.
David  can you see it?
DAVID: I'll see. Um...
- Sho.
- SHO: Yes?
Can you re-flood the airlock?
(AIR HISSING)
You tell me when.
SHO: Okay.
(SNIFFLING)
DAVID: Did she close that valve?
MIRANDA: Yeah  yeah  she closed it.
Okay.
What other way could it get in?
The thrusters.
The manifolds in the thruster nozzles.
If it tries one  we could blast it off.
But we'd have to know which.
DAVID: It's too dark. I can't see anything.
- Shit.
- MIRANDA: There must be some way.
Thruster sensors.
If it climbs in the nozzle
the temperature should move.
Should.
All right.
(GASPS)
- There.
- Thruster two firing.
(RUMBLING)
Miranda  can you reach Tranquility?
(GRUNTS)
We missed. Cut it.
Guys  it's heading toward... No  wait!
No  no  it's heading towards the lab.
It's fast.
DAVID: I'm sorry  guys  I can't see.
HUGH: It's okay  we're watching.
- Kibo.
- Thruster three firing.
(RUMBLING)
(WHISPERS) Come on.
Please  please.
Quest this time.
- David  can you see?
- DAVID: No  I'm...
- Thruster five.
- Sorry. I'm sorry  I can't...
(RUMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
MIRANDA: Sho?
(RAPID BEEPING)
(ALARM BLARING)
(ALARM STOPS)
DAVID: What was that?
We've burned through too much fuel.
- There.
- SHO: We were already low after the Pilgrim.
Doc  listen  all this thrusting
we've placed ourselves into decaying orbit.
- DAVID: Shit.
- We'll reach atmosphere soon
if I don't get us back to stable.
And I'll need the rest
of the fuel to do it
- if we even have that much.
- No. David?
David  we can't risk Calvin
riding us down into the atmosphere  okay?
But I don't know... Could it survive that?
HUGH: We don't know.
It's already gone well beyond
what any living organism
should be able to survive.
(PANTING)
MIRANDA: If it's between letting it in here
or letting it down there
we let it in here.
Where are you?
(♪♪♪)
HUGH: We've just let it back in here.
(RUMBLING)
SHO: Moving us back into stable orbit.
These creatures could have dominated Mars
for hundreds of millions of years.
But now we know that they hibernate
with a loss of atmosphere.
If we deprive it of air
retreat in Tranquility
and seal ourselves off...
MIRANDA: And vent the rest of the station.
Exactly.
No life support  no life.
MIRANDA: Right.
Okay  Hugh and I will
sweep from Quest east.
And  um  you and Sho scour the poles
and  uh  lock off each compartment.
(BEEPING)
(METALLIC CREAKING)
(♪♪♪)
(GASPING SOFTLY)
(WHIRRING  CLACKING)
(♪♪♪)
(RIPPING)
(HISSES)
SHO: (PANTING) It will take about
four hours to vent all oxygen.
MIRANDA: What do we do till then?
DAVID: We wait.
You okay?
Derry  look at me.
- (WEAKLY) Hmm?
- You okay?
I'm fine.
I remember the day the Challenger blew up.
They took us out of school early
I remember that day.
It's hard to watch people die.
(♪♪♪)
Like  uh...
Fireworks.
HUGH: "Up  up"
"the long  delirious  burning blue"
"I've topped the wind-swept heights
with ease and grace"
Best eulogy ever.
DAVID: Hmm.
Rory says
"Don't give me a eulogy."
"Give me a parachute."
(HUGH CHUCKLING)
(SIGHS)
He was my buddy.
(WHISPERS) It's my fault.
It's all my fault.
Maybe it was your fault
maybe it was my fault  maybe...
I don't know  it doesn't matter  does it?
Getting this thing on board was a risk
and we knew it from the beginning.
I took it.
HUGH: It's just surviving.
Life's very existence requires destruction.
Calvin doesn't hate us.
But he has to kill us
in order to survive.
DAVID: Hugh.
- Hugh. Hugh.
- Hugh.
(HUGH GROANS)
DAVID: All right  all right.
- Hey.
- Derry?
Hugh?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry  because of all the...
- Hugh?
(RAPID BEEPING)
Hugh?
DAVID: Hugh? There's no output.
God  get the defib.
- Get him back.
- Okay.
- Get him down.
- MIRANDA: I'll strap him in.
DAVID: Take off the sling  okay?
SHO: Yeah.
MIRANDA: Sho  get the ACLS kit
and the defibrillator.
(FLATLINING TONE)
DAVID: Shit.
SHO: Here.
MIRANDA: Prep the defibrillator
and get the shocks down.
MIRANDA: 360 joules.
DAVID: Yeah.
DAVID: Copy  360 joules.
Charging. Clear.
(THUMP)
DAVID: Charging. Shooting.
MIRANDA: Still fibrillating.
Just stack the shocks if you have to.
- Go  360.
- All right. Clear.
DAVID: (WHISPERS) Shit.
- Nothing.
- Go again  360.
- Go again. Hit him.
- Clear.
DAVID: All right.
(THUMP)
All right  all right. I got output.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Okay  sinus rate 98 BPM.
DAVID: You really scared me there  buddy.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
David?
(WHISPERS) Fuck.
What is this?
DAVID: Stabilizing.
(ALL GASPING)
Get the plasma cutter.
MIRANDA: Calvin's feeding off his leg.
DAVID: Shit!
(ELECTRONIC WHIR)
Miranda!
(MIRANDA GASPS)
DAVID: Go. Get out of here.
Let's go!
Miranda  let's go! Pull it away from Hugh.
Sho.
- We'll come back for him!
- Miranda! Come on! Let's go!
DAVID: Sho!
No!
Sho!
No! Shit.
Hey  guys?
(FEEDBACK SQUEALING)
Shit.
(♪♪♪)
(CRACKLING  CREAKING)
(HUGH EXHALES)
Calvin?
MIRANDA: We don't know where he is.
(HUGH SIGHS)
- Where's Sho?
- MIRANDA: He'll be fine.
We stopped all oxygen
venting in the station.
(HUGH GROANING)
Lift me up.
(HUGH EXHALES)
MIRANDA: Okay.
Okay.
HUGH: (WHISPERS) Oh  Miranda.
(♪♪♪)
(BREATHING WEAKLY)
I'm up.
(SLOW  STEADY BEEPING)
(FLATLINING TONE)
(♪♪♪)
(SOBBING QUIETLY)
(PANTING)
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
I'm coming home  Mei.
MIRANDA: I know what
I feel is not scientific.
It's not rational.
I feel hate.
I feel pure...
fucking...
...hate for that thing.
(ELECTRONIC PINGING)
(PINGING)
Calvin.
How is that moving like that?
He must have swallowed
the marker on Derry's leg.
Yeah.
(PINGING CONTINUES)
We can track him.
(♪♪♪)
(PINGING)
(PINGING CONTINUES)
(♪♪♪)
(MIRANDA GASPS)
DAVID: Let's kill this thing.
Venting Zarya now.
(BEEPING)
(MIRANDA PANTING)
Okay  it's suffocating.
- How long do you think that's gonna take?
- I don't know.
(ALARM BEEPING)
Shit.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Proximity alert. Proximity alert.
Proximity...
They're coming.
Kat's distress call must
have reached Earth.
Wait  where are they docking?
Shit.
- Looks like Zarya.
- Jesus  that's where Calvin is.
Station to Soyuz.
Station to Soyuz  do you copy?
- Station to Soyuz  do you copy?
- MIRANDA: Try the flashlight.
DAVID: (WHISPERS) Come on  come on.
They can't see this.
Must be too reflective.
(GRUNTS)
(RUMBLING)
(GASPING BREATHS)
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
DAVID: Shit.
What the fuck are they doing?
David.
David!
They're not coming to rescue us.
It's Firewall Three.
What?
Firewall One was the box.
And Firewall Two was the lab.
And Firewall Three is the station.
But we have a new firewall.
- What are you saying?
- MIRANDA: They don't know that.
And if Firewall One or Two fail
they have two choices.
They can contain  or they expel.
They're pushing us out to deep space.
They cannot risk Calvin reaching Earth.
That was my protocol.
I insisted from the beginning
and the committee agreed.
They all put their names to it.
The list is as long as your arm.
Now  protecting firewalls is my job
and if we would have succeeded
we could have gone home.
And if we failed...
Wait for me  Mei.
(BEEPING)
(CLICKING  BEEPING)
DAVID: Sho. Oh  he thinks it's a rescue.
Oh  God. He's heading towards Calvin.
We have to stop him.
(PANTING)
Sho!
Sho  can you hear us?
(STRAINED GRUNT)
(♪♪♪)
(METALLIC THUD)
DAVID: Sho!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
MIRANDA: Sho!
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(MUFFLED BOOMING)
(YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
(BEEPING)
(YELLING)
(YELLING  GROANING)
DAVID: Sho!
- Miranda!
- Sho!
Sho?
- DAVID: Sho!
- Take my hand  Sho!
Don't let go  Sho!
(SHO GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
MIRANDA: No!
No! No  don't let go!
Sho! No  Sho! No!
- No!
- SHO: Let go!
No! Sho! Sho!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Miranda!
(GRUNTING)
MIRANDA: No!
- Come on!
- No!
Miranda!
(GASPS)
Miranda! Let's go!
(RUMBLING)
(DEEP CREAKING)
The CPU is still up. It's a miracle.
We're  uh...
We're losing life support.
The temperature is dropping rapidly.
Atmosphere is venting from everywhere
and I don't know how to stop it.
Okay  how much time do we have?
In here? Uh  two hours  maybe an hour 45...
But it  uh...
- What?
- Fuck.
- Fuck!
- What? What is it? What?
We're  uh...
We're not moving into space. The opposite.
All that fucked-up thrusting
we're decaying again.
What?
Sho has a subroutine here.
Um...
Without any correction in course  which
we don't have any fuel for anyway  um...
We'll hit the atmosphere in  uh...
39 minutes.
We're not gonna survive reentry.
(WRY CHUCKLE)
Calvin could.
(TREMBLING BREATHING)
(♪♪♪)
(MIRANDA SHIVERING)
It's so cold.
(SHIVERING STOPS)
DAVID: Hmm.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Mmm.
My father used to read this to me
when I was a kid.
(♪♪♪)
(SHIVERING SOFTLY)
"Good night  room."
"Good night  moon."
"Good night  cow jumping over the moon."
(SOFT  TREMBLING LAUGH)
DAVID: "Good night  light."
"And the red balloon."
(SNIFFLES)
(♪♪♪)
"Good night  nobody."
(DAVID SNIFFLES)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
MIRANDA: I remember when I saw
my first picture of Earth.
And I asked my father where all those...
All those lines were.
The borders.
(BOTH CHUCKLE SOFTLY)
(WHISPERS) I really miss him.
(♪♪♪)
Good night  moon.
Good night  stars.
Good night  air.
(MIRANDA SHIVERING)
Bait.
Calvin needs oxygen to survive.
With the 02 levels so low
in the rest of the ship
it will be drawn to the oxygen candles.
- We can use them as bait.
- Yeah.
There are two lifeboats  A and B
both set to default entry trajectory.
You press the button
they autopilot themselves to the surface
unless somebody...
Somebody overrides them from the inside.
I use the oxygen candles
to lure Calvin into Boat A.
I close the hatch. I press the button
to give me full manual control.
And if I can hold the stick
I can override the flight path.
And if I hold it long enough
I can avoid reentry.
(STUTTERING) You fly out into deep space.
With Calvin. Yes.
(STAMMERING) Meanwhile
you get into Boat B
you press the button
and if there are no complications
- then it'd take you back home.
- No.
No  we should lure Calvin together.
- No  Miranda.
- Yeah.
That doesn't make any sense.
Why?
The lifeboats are meant for one person.
And this has been your plan all along.
To make sure that
that creature doesn't get to Earth.
Then I should be Plan A.
No  I'm a pilot.
You're Plan B.
Listen  listen.
I belong up here.
DAVID: Hmm.
I don't want to go back down
to eight billion of those motherfuckers.
(CRYING LAUGH)
(SNIFFLES)
I need you to say you trust me.
Yeah?
I do.
I trust you.
DAVID: Wait here. I'll signal you.
(WHIRRING  CLACK)
(SHIVERING)
(♪♪♪)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
(COUGHING)
(RAPID BEEPING)
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
(CLATTERING NEARBY)
(SHIVERING)
(GASPS) Hey! Shit!
Whoa.
(GASPING BREATHS)
Shit!
(SHIVERING)
(BEEPING)
(PANTING)
Fuck.
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING BREATHS)
(GASPING)
Okay.
This is Mission Specialist
Dr. David A. Jordan
commanding Soyuz Lifeboat A  2233 UTC.
ISS has entered catastrophic orbital decay.
Initiating emergency escape sequence
in five
four  three
two  one.
(LOUD RUMBLING)
(GASPING)
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
(♪♪♪)
(BEEPING)
Come on  Miranda  get going.
(GRUNTS)
(BEEPS)
DAVID: Initiating manual override.
(PANTING)
(BEEPING)
This is Dr. Miranda North
black box recording
in case of death upon reentry.
The creature killed
four of the six ISS astronauts
with a fifth  Dr. David Jordan
presumed dead
carrying it out into deep space.
My five colleagues all sacrificed themselves
to maintain the firewall  so  please
honor them
for giving everything to this cause.
Mars life-forms should
be considered hostile.
Do not underestimate their intelligence
and their adaptive capabilities.
Now  we did not learn
how to restrain or eliminate it
but if this creature ever reaches Earth
use every available resource to destroy it
or you will risk all human life.
(ALARM BLARING)
(ALARM STOPS)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(PAINED GROAN)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
(STRAINED GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
(GRUNTS)
(♪♪♪)
(SOFTLY) You can do it. You can do it.
You can do it.
Come on!
(WHOOSHING)
(BIRD SQUAWKING)
(MAN SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
(SPEAKS VIETNAMESE)
DAVID: No  no  no. No!
MIRANDA: (SCREAMING) No! No!
No!
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
No! No!
DAVID: No! No!
(MEN SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
No!
No  no  no!
No  no  no  no!
(♪♪♪)
When I die and they lay me to rest
Gonna go to the place that's the best
When I lay me down to die
Goin' up to the spirit in the sky
That's where I'm gonna go when I die
When I die and they lay me to rest
I'm gonna go to the place that's the best
Go to the place that's the best
(♪♪♪)
Improved & Synced by BanglarBagh